<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mantenance Archives - TicTAP</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/tag/mantenance/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en/</link>
	<description>Convierte tus productos y servicios en Smart</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:59:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cropped-sello_445-32x32.png</url>
	<title>mantenance Archives - TicTAP</title>
	<link>/en/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The 5 main indicators (KPI’s) for the maintenance of facilities</title>
		<link>/en/blog-en/the-5-main-indicators-kpis-for-the-maintenance-of-facilities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 17:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mantenance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-5-main-indicators-kpis-for-the-maintenance-of-facilities/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As we saw in the article the facilities maintenance plan and the 7 steps to create it , to ensure that the operation plan is giving the expected results, we must analyze the main indicators of performance (KPI&#8217;s) defined. The question to ask ourselves here then is: What KPI’s should I consider in my plant &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/blog-en/the-5-main-indicators-kpis-for-the-maintenance-of-facilities/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The 5 main indicators (KPI’s) for the maintenance of facilities</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog-en/the-5-main-indicators-kpis-for-the-maintenance-of-facilities/">The 5 main indicators (KPI’s) for the maintenance of facilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="10988" class="elementor elementor-10988 elementor-8257">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<div class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4190d4c elementor-section-content-top tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section tictap-text-dark elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4190d4c" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-c16f306" data-id="c16f306" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-0c807f1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="0c807f1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>As we saw in the article <a href = "/que-es-un-plan-de-mantenimiento-de-instalaciones-y-equipos-y-7-pasos-para- create it / "target =" _ blank "rel =" noopener "> the facilities maintenance plan and the 7 steps to create it </a>, to ensure that the operation plan is giving the expected results, we must analyze the main indicators of performance (KPI&#8217;s) defined. The question to ask ourselves here then is: What KPI’s should I consider in my plant and equipment maintenance plan?</p>
<p>There really is no single answer to this question. The maintenance indicators that we must consider will always ultimately depend on the type of installation and machinery, the objectives that they must meet, etc.</p>
<p>However, there are some very common main maintenance indicators that you may want to consider in your maintenance plan if you have not already done so:</p>
<h2> Maintenance indicators </h2>
<h3> KPI 1. Corrective versus preventive maintenance relationship </h3>
<p>This KPI is about being able to see the amount of preventive maintenance work done relative to the amount of corrective work done.<br />
We will obtain this metric as follows: number of hours in corrective tasks / number of hours in preventive tasks.</p>
<p>Initially, the goal to achieve is 0.5. In other words, for each hours of corrective work, 2 hours of preventive work have been performed.</p>
<p>Obtaining this maintenance indicator or KPI has a low degree of difficulty. In some cases, the only difficulty is that it is not always easy to draw a line between preventive and corrective tasks. To solve it, we can generate a good manual that helps to solve the doubts in this regard.</p>
<h3> KPI 2. Downtime / month </h3>
<p>With this maintenance indicator we will collect the downtime of the installation or machinery per month. It is measured in hours and the metric to calculate it is simply the sum of the hours of inactivity of the facility or equipment.</p>
<p>The goal or recommended value would be that the value of this KPI does not exceed 10%. Anyway, it would be ideal if it could be 1% or less.</p>
<h3> KPI 3. Preventive maintenance tasks completed by meeting the date </h3>
<p>This KPI consists of the percentage of the number of preventive tasks completed on time. With this KPI we can control if the prevention tasks are being carried out and completed in the times we have planned.</p>
<p>The metric to calculate it is:</p>
<p>(Number of preventive tasks completed on time / total number of planned preventive tasks) * 100</p>
<p>A recommended goal or value for this maintenance indicator is for the result to be greater than 85%.</p>
<p><span style = "font-size: 20px; font-style: normal; -webkit-text-size-adjust: 100%;"> As in other types of health indicators, obtaining this KPI is quite simple because only It requires keeping an updated and detailed record of the maintenance tasks we carry out, as well as a report of the execution times. The CMMS we use should be able to allow us to easily record this information. </span></p>
<h3> KPI 4. Response time of the maintenance department </h3>
<h4> <strong> Why this KPI is important for your company </strong> </h4>
<p>The maintenance indicators related to preventive maintenance may seem more critical given the importance of this type of maintenance to ensure the availability of the machinery and extend its useful life. However, if you have a maintenance team for your facilities and work teams and there is a breakdown, it will be extremely important for you to be able to determine if the response from the maintenance team is fast enough.</p>
<p>In the event that you are a maintenance company, your speed of response in the event of a breakdown in a client&#8217;s facilities or machinery is also critical. It can be a key differential value for you compared to your competition, as well as the key to maintaining good service and high customer satisfaction.</p>
<p>Thus, in our maintenance plan, the KPI that allows us to monitor the speed of response in corrective maintenance cannot be missing.</p>
<h4> <strong> How to determine and measure the response speed to failure or breakdown </strong> </h4>
<p>To design this indicator we must consider the resources available to the maintenance department or our maintenance company, and the type of incident reported. It is therefore necessary for the report to have specific details.</p>
<p>The analysis of this KPI will allow us, that is, the value obtained, will allow us to determine if we are offering the desired response speed in order to develop fast and efficient attention processes in the event of a breakdown by the maintenance team. In this way, we will minimize waiting times and machinery downtime.</p>
<p>To measure it, we will measure from the time the maintenance request is reported or registered until the time our team began corrective maintenance tasks to solve the fault or failure.</p>
<p>Determining what value this indicator should have will vary greatly depending on the industry. For example, the desired value for this KPI in facilities of industries that work with chemicals or hazardous substances may be higher than in other types of industries. In any case, 5 hours can be considered as a standard value.</p>
<p>The difficulty of obtaining this KPI is usually low. A highly recommended way to achieve this is to have automated software to record warning and solution events and to easily generate and have a history.</p>
<h3> KPI 5. Number of incidents resolved by first level of plant </h3>
<p>This KPI collects as a percentage the number of incidents or breakdowns that are reported and that are finally reported immediately by the same First Level Plant personnel.</p>
<p>To measure it we will use the metric: (Number of clients reported and resolved by Pirmer staff Level of Plant / Total number of breakdowns and failures reported) * 100</p>
<p>It is convenient that the goal to be achieved for this KPI is a percentage higher than 25%.</p>
<p>The difficulty in achieving this value will depend on whether our CMMS allows to record this value easily or automatically. In the cases in which this value is registered with manual systems, without systematizing, it is usually more expensive to obtain it and to be reliable.</p>
<h3> KPI 6: Budgeted costs versus actual costs </h3>
<p>Like everything in life, one thing is what you plan and another what you really get. Thus, in the maintenance plan we will have defined the budget for maintenance and determined how this budget is distributed. With this KPI we can confirm if we are meeting this budget. This can be defined on an annual or quarterly basis.</p>
<p>If the budget is exceeded too often, we will have to analyze the reasons in order to find the solution.</p>
<p>To calculate this KPI we must consider the costs involved in maintenance: from the cost of personnel to the cost of material. The material cost means that we must consider both the number and the cost of the parts required for maintenance. This parameter will also allow us to identify if we are ordering large and expensive orders during repairs, which should be considered when ordering new equipment and parts for stock.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-b086c86 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--top tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b086c86" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;,&quot;background_background&quot;:&quot;classic&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-fc1b807" data-id="fc1b807" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-75280a4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="75280a4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3 style = "text-align: center;"> Discover how TicTAP can help you manage the maintenance of facilities and work equipment </h3>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-9c3c1c4 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--bottom tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="9c3c1c4" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-50a9f53" data-id="50a9f53" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-effd1f9 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="effd1f9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a href="/en/contact/" target="_blank" class="elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-sm" role="button" id="contact_fromBLOG1">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">Contact us</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog-en/the-5-main-indicators-kpis-for-the-maintenance-of-facilities/">The 5 main indicators (KPI’s) for the maintenance of facilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is a work equipment or facilities maintenance model?</title>
		<link>/en/uncategorized/what-is-a-work-equipment-or-facilities-maintenance-model/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 12:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-is-a-work-equipment-or-facilities-maintenance-model/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are different types of maintenance, as we discussed in the article What types of maintenance are there and can I apply to my facilities and work teams? In that same article we also anticipate that it is not usually the case that a single type of maintenance is sufficient for each installation or work &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/uncategorized/what-is-a-work-equipment-or-facilities-maintenance-model/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What is a work equipment or facilities maintenance model?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/uncategorized/what-is-a-work-equipment-or-facilities-maintenance-model/">What is a work equipment or facilities maintenance model?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="9460" class="elementor elementor-9460 elementor-8108">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<div class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4190d4c elementor-section-content-top tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4190d4c" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-c16f306" data-id="c16f306" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-0c807f1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="0c807f1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>There are different types of maintenance, as we discussed in the article <a href = "/que-tipos-de-mantenimiento-existen-y-puedo-aplicar-a-mis-instalaciones- y-work-teams / "> What types of maintenance are there and can I apply to my facilities and work teams? </a> <span style =" font-size: 20px; font-style: normal; -webkit -text-size-adjust: 100%; "> In that same article we also anticipate that it is not usually the case that a single type of maintenance is sufficient for each installation or work team, but that we will need a model of facilities maintenance . </span></p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-b0ca406 elementor-section-content-top tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b0ca406" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;background_background&quot;:&quot;classic&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-f45c754" data-id="f45c754" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-dc1cf42 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="dc1cf42" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>The facility maintenance model consists of determining what combination of the different types of maintenance and in what proportions they are required according to the needs of each facility or equipment.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b11bb9d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="b11bb9d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Of all the possible activities included in the different models, there are two that are common to all of them and that we will find in any facility maintenance model. The reason is that they have been proven to be highly profitable to apply on any equipment. These two activities that you should always consider in your maintenance model, whatever it is, are:</p>
<ol>
<li> <strong> Visual inspections </strong>: they allow detecting a possible fault early and, therefore, its solution will probably be cheaper than if we wait for the problem to get worse. </li>
<li> <strong> Lubrication </strong> with products appropriate to the characteristics of the equipment. Although it involves a cost because it requires the appropriate lubricant product and the labor to apply it, performing this task will always be cheaper than repairing the equipment due to a lack of lubricant. </li>
</ol>
<p>Maintenance models may present variations or deviations, but there are four fundamental types that you can apply in the maintenance of your facilities, as we will see in the next article.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e90d66d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="e90d66d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="655" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min-300x192.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min-768x491.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-b086c86 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--top tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b086c86" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-fc1b807" data-id="fc1b807" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-75280a4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="75280a4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3 style = "text-align: center;"> Discover how TicTAP can help you manage the maintenance of facilities and work equipment </h3>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-9c3c1c4 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--bottom tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="9c3c1c4" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-50a9f53" data-id="50a9f53" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e4e1b84 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="e4e1b84" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a href="/en/contact/" class="elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-sm" role="button" id="botonContacto_Blog4">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">Haz clic aquí</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/uncategorized/what-is-a-work-equipment-or-facilities-maintenance-model/">What is a work equipment or facilities maintenance model?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What types of maintenance exist and can I apply to my facilities and work equipment?</title>
		<link>/en/blog-en/what-types-of-maintenance-exist-and-can-i-apply-to-my-facilities-and-work-equipment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/what-types-of-maintenance-exist-and-can-i-apply-to-my-facilities-and-work-equipment/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It may be that you have your own facilities or work teams to maintain, or that you are a facility maintenance company. In any of the cases, you need to know perfectly the types of maintenance of facilities and work equipment that exist, and be very clear which one or which ones are convenient for &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/blog-en/what-types-of-maintenance-exist-and-can-i-apply-to-my-facilities-and-work-equipment/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What types of maintenance exist and can I apply to my facilities and work equipment?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog-en/what-types-of-maintenance-exist-and-can-i-apply-to-my-facilities-and-work-equipment/">What types of maintenance exist and can I apply to my facilities and work equipment?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="9458" class="elementor elementor-9458 elementor-7830">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<div class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4190d4c elementor-section-content-top tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4190d4c" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-c16f306" data-id="c16f306" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-0c807f1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="0c807f1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>It may be that you have your own facilities or work teams to maintain, or that you are a facility maintenance company. In any of the cases, you need to know perfectly the types of maintenance of facilities and work equipment that exist, and be very clear which one or which ones are convenient for you to carry out.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-b0ca406 elementor-section-content-top tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b0ca406" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;background_background&quot;:&quot;classic&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-f45c754" data-id="f45c754" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-dc1cf42 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="dc1cf42" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>The maintenance of facilities and work equipment consists of carrying out all those actions and actions necessary in them to avoid failures and breakdowns. Its objective is to ensure the operation and availability of such equipment and facilities.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b11bb9d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="b11bb9d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2> General classification of types of maintenance of facilities and work equipment </h2>
<p>There are several types of maintenance of facilities and equipment that we can perform. However, all of them can be classified into two groups:</p>
<ol>
<li> <strong> Reaction maintenance: </strong> Carrying out tasks or intervention in the installation or work equipment due to an error, a breakdown or due to the wear of the components. Thus, it suddenly appears sued by the facility or equipment itself. This is usually due to system obsolescence or misuse. Corrective maintenance would enter this group. </li>
<li> <strong> Anticipation maintenance: </strong> This group includes those maintenance with a proactive approach. They consist of carrying out tasks to:
<ol>
<li> Minimize the risk of breakdown or failure </li>
<li> Guarantee the availability and proper functioning of the installation or work team </li>
<li> Gain control over the facility or equipment </li>
</ol>
<p>In this group we would find, among others, preventive and predictive maintenance. </li>
</ol>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e90d66d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="e90d66d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="794" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-2-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-2-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-2-min-300x233.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-2-min-768x596.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-f5d2469 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="f5d2469" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Detailed classification of types of maintenance of facilities and work equipment</h3>
<p>The types of maintenance have been classified over time as follows according to the type of tasks they include:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong> Preventive maintenance: </strong> This type of maintenance is based on determining the vulnerable points of the equipment and scheduling interventions at these points to carry them out at the most opportune moment. The objective of this type of maintenance is to be able to maintain a certain level of service for the equipment.</li>
<li><strong> Predictive maintenance: </strong> It is based on being able to have the values ​​of certain variables to be able to know and permanently report on the status and operation of the facilities. These variables can be such as temperature, vibration, power consumption, etc.</li>
<li><strong> Corrective maintenance: </strong> It consists of correcting defects or problems that occur in the equipment and that the users themselves report to the company or facility maintenance department. If only this type of maintenance is carried out, as you can imagine, what we are doing is leaving the equipment to its fate and we do not take care of it until it has a breakdown or failure.</li>
<li><strong> Zero Hour Maintenance (Overhaul): </strong> It consists of performing a set of tasks at scheduled intervals before any failure appears or when the reliability of the equipment has decreased, so it is difficult to make forecasts of its productive capacity. In this case, the revision is based on leaving the equipment to zero maintenance hours or, in other words, as if the cinchona were new. In these same revisions, the elements subject to wear are also replaced or repaired. The objective is to ensure in advance and with great probability a good working time of the equipment.</li>
<li><strong> Maintenance in use: </strong> It is the basic equipment&#8217;s maintenance that can be carried out by the users of the equipment. It is based on performing a series of simple tasks, such as data collection, a visual inspection, or lubrication. In any case, they are simple tasks that do not require special training.</li>
</ol>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-579cea9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="579cea9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="690" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-3-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-3-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-3-min-300x202.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-3-min-768x518.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b3eea82 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="b3eea82" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2> What maintenance should I apply to the facilities or work teams that I manage? </h2>
<p>When determining what type of maintenance your facilities require, the answer is that it depends on the equipment and, in addition, it will not be a single type of maintenance but, whatever the installation situation, it will probably require a combination of these types maintenance.<br />
Therefore, when deciding which combination of these types of maintenance are ideal for each team, it is best to consider several aspects, including:</p>
<ul>
<li> Cost caused in production due to equipment stoppage </li>
<li> Repair cost </li>
<li> Environmental impact </li>
<li> Security </li>
<li> Quality of the product or service </li>
</ul>
<p>Due to the difficulty of being able to determine the maintenance to be carried out on an equipment according to the previous classification, the most practical thing to do is to think about maintenance models. A maintenance model consists of the combination of different types of maintenance in a piece of equipment so that the set is the most appropriate both in its selection and in the proportion.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-14be255 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="14be255" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>&lt;h3&gt; Tool for the management and control of maintenance of facilities and work equipment &lt;/h3&gt;<br />
When performing any of these maintenance, it will be convenient to have a system that helps the operator and users to be able to record in the simplest, most effective and productive way possible the results of the tests, the values ​​of the observed variables, etc. as well as information about the maintenance itself, that is, who performed it, when, etc.</p>
<p>The TicTAP platform allows the operator or user with permissions to bring their mobile closer to the equipment label and fill in the appropriate form. All the forms and data collected are centrally registered on the platform and automatically available to the entire maintenance team.</p>
<p>In addition, these operators and users with permissions, will be able to access, through the TicTAP label and from their own mobile, other useful information for the maintenance of the equipment, such as the maintenance history of each equipment or the user manual .</p>
<p>And all this without requiring expensive infrastructures or applications, but simply with the application of TictAP labels in your facilities.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-b086c86 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--top tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b086c86" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-fc1b807" data-id="fc1b807" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-75280a4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="75280a4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3 style = "text-align: center;"> Discover how TicTAP can help you manage the maintenance of facilities and work equipment </h3>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-9c3c1c4 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--bottom tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="9c3c1c4" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-50a9f53" data-id="50a9f53" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-8a0c884 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="8a0c884" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a href="/en/contact/" class="elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-sm" role="button" id="botonContacto_Blog5">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">Contact us</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog-en/what-types-of-maintenance-exist-and-can-i-apply-to-my-facilities-and-work-equipment/">What types of maintenance exist and can I apply to my facilities and work equipment?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
