<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>asset traceability Archives - TicTAP</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/tag/asset-traceability/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en/</link>
	<description>Mantenimiento y trazabilidad de activos.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 08:38:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cropped-sello_445-32x32.png</url>
	<title>asset traceability Archives - TicTAP</title>
	<link>/en/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to turn your products into intelligent items to boost customer loyalty and sales.</title>
		<link>/en/blog/how-to-turn-your-products-into-intelligent-items-to-boost-customer-loyalty-and-sales/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asset traceability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFC Tags]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/how-to-turn-your-products-into-intelligent-items-to-boost-customer-loyalty-and-sales/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You can turn any product or facility you manage into smart objects to differentiate yourself from competitors, optimize your work and increase sales.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog/how-to-turn-your-products-into-intelligent-items-to-boost-customer-loyalty-and-sales/">How to turn your products into intelligent items to boost customer loyalty and sales.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="12860" class="elementor elementor-12860 elementor-10887">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<div class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4190d4c elementor-section-content-top tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section tictap-text-dark elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4190d4c" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-c16f306" data-id="c16f306" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-0c807f1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="0c807f1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Nowadays there are smart refrigerators. These are the wonderful refrigerator models that offer a wide range of functions to make life easier for the user. Even some of these smart objects come with a voice assistant included. Just talk to the fridge to find out the expiration date of a product or make the purchase online.</p>
<p>The really wonderful thing about it would be to be able to transfer this intelligence to any object, don’t you think? That is, that any object could give the user the information he needs, warn him of certain events, etc.</p>
<p>You may think that it is not feasible for any object to offer these possibilities. It may seem unpayable to you to make the conversion from an inert object to an intelligent object. Or you might think it’s not worth it if the object or machine is not high-end and of a certain minimum price.</p>
<p>However, there is nothing further from reality.  <span style="font-size: 20px; font-style: normal;"><b>With TicTAP you can convert any </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-5ffcee0 elementor-section-content-top tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="5ffcee0" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;background_background&quot;:&quot;classic&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-e0c0c88" data-id="e0c0c88" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-81ec8e1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="81ec8e1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>If you apply it to the products you sell or to the facilities you manage (boiler rooms, conditioned appliances, elevators, etc.), <strong>this conversion can be the key to differentiate yourself from the competition and optimize your work</strong>. </p>
<p>In other words: <strong>improve your sales and performance</strong>. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-802384b elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="802384b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>The reason for this statement is that the conversion of your products or installations into intelligent objects will allow you to:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Optimize work systems</strong> in your company</li>
<li><<strong>Differentiate yourself</strong> from the competition</li>
<li>Even<strong> create a one-channela-one with your customers</strong> for<strong> loyalty and increase your sales</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>In this article we explain:</p>
<ol>
<li> How to do it.  </li>
<li>Some of the main features you could add to your products or installations, and the benefits they would have for your business. </li>
</ol>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e90d66d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="e90d66d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-estrategia-diferenciarse-optimizar-min.jpeg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-estrategia-diferenciarse-optimizar-min.jpeg 1025w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-estrategia-diferenciarse-optimizar-min-300x200.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-estrategia-diferenciarse-optimizar-min-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-11d0336 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="11d0336" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>From inert objects to intelligent objects</h2>
<p>To convert the objects you want into intelligent elements, <strong>the first step is to have a TicTAP account and order TicTAP-NFC</strong> tags. It is also possible to create QR codes from the TicTAP platform. So you can print them yourself, without having to request the NFC tags.</p>
<p>Now, <strong>if you want to offer the convenience of contactless from the mobile to your users/customers</strong> when they interact with the smart object through their own mobile, you will need the<strong> TicTAP NFC</strong> tags. </p>
<p>As we said before, all this <strong>at a much more affordable price than any other </strong>alternative you can think of (Internet of Things, apps developed by your IT team to measure, etc). </p>
<p><strong>From the TicTAP platform you can create as many webapps as you want</strong>. The system is based on templates, forms, etc. You can create them yourself by dragging and dropping ( drag &#038; drop) the elements you want on each page/form of the webapp. <strong>You do not need to have an IT</strong> machine. </p>
<p>If instead of selling specific products, <strong>manages the maintenance of products or systems</strong> (maintenance of fire extinguishers, elevators, machine rooms, etc.), the system is the same. You only need to attach TicTAP NFC tags to each of these items to manage</strong>. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-fee750d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="fee750d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-simple-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-simple-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-simple-min-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-simple-min-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-86e1758 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="86e1758" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>Benefits of offering smart objects</h2>
<p>The list of benefits of turning products into smart objects is long. Below we highlight the main benefits that will help you improve sales and customer loyalty.  </p>
<h3>The object itself provides the information to the user</h3>
<p>How many times does a user want to interact with a machine and get desperate looking for the instruction manual, if at all? </p>
<p>Simple situations such as knowing what consumable material would be recommended by the manufacturer or seller (you); or that the power goes out and when the user returns he needs to reconfigure the product; or that in a factory he wants to know how a particular machine should be maintained. </p>
<p>For the user it is ideal as you only require a mobile phone placed close to the TicTAP NFC tag that is on the same machine (or asset) and access the webapp with a password. There you can have made available both the user manual, as well as parts that are compatible for repairs, assemblies, etc. You can even provide them with the link to order new consumables or spare parts. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4056e45 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="4056e45" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="756" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-satisfaction-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-satisfaction-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-satisfaction-min-300x221.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-satisfaction-min-768x567.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02b2e94 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="02b2e94" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Maximize the impact of your marketing actions by sending your promotions only to customers who will be interested<br />
Every time we receive in the mail more offers, newsletters with promotions, etc. The volume of this type of emails is so high that users are getting a finer filter, so we only open those messages that really interest us. The rest are often marked as Spam.</p>
<p>That’s why it’s so important that the message title resonates with the recipient. But as good as you write and very creative as you are with the titles, if what you offer is not interested, no one will buy you anything. Your messages will be perceived as noise and users will unsubscribe. </p>
<p>Fortunately, there is now a way to know which customers who have purchased a product from us may be interested in a specific promotion.  So we can send it only to them.  There is also a way to send the message to the mobile as notification instead of as mail, where you compete with so much newsletter.  This way is TicTAP.</p>
<p>Imagine a company that sells laser printers to companies. Each printer is added a TicTAP label. Thanks to it, customers make their toner orders by bringing their mobile to the printer. This month the selling company wants to promote the purchase of toners, but only those of certain models. From the TicTAP management platform you can send a mobile notification to users with the promotion. It does indicate that it is only received by customers of printer models for which the promotion makes sense.</p>
<p>In this way, users receive notifications that can really interest them. They will never receive the announcement of a promotion related to a model they do not have. So in the mid term they will perceive your ads as valuable, as they will be truly personalized and relevant to them</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6d23ac2 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="6d23ac2" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-optimiza-tu-sistema.jpeg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-optimiza-tu-sistema.jpeg 1025w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-optimiza-tu-sistema-300x200.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-optimiza-tu-sistema-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-1aa8812 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="1aa8812" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Offers direct contact to customers to gain their trust</h3>
<p>When a machine, appliance, object, etc. breaks, a tare is present or you need some kind of spare part/consumable material, and you have to look for contact information about the manufacturer or seller, it is very frustrating how much it costs to find it. </p>
<p>This is also the typical time when there is no way to find out how to contact the manufacturer or the seller. When you finally find a phone or a contact email on the web, when you call or write they forward you to another. </p>
<p>In these cases the client wants an easy and direct channel to express his discontent. What he wants is to be able to say: &#8220;hey! I am here, with this product that I have bought you depositing my trust in you, and now it does not work or I have doubts about an aspect and I do not find who to ask&#8221;. In addition, in this situation the customer wants to feel heard as quickly and easily as possible. </p>
<p>Again, you can make it easier for your customers to contact you using TicTAP. Through its management platform, you can create a screen with contact information and even with a contact form. </p>
<p>In the event that the client has a problem, just zoom in on the mobile and the webapp you created will open. In it, you can access that screen and contact you easily through the channel you have determined (phone, e-mail, etc). </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6bb67e2 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="6bb67e2" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-trust-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-trust-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-trust-min-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-client-trust-min-768x513.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-5237246 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="5237246" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Record the revisions in the smart object itself to optimize your work system</h3>
<p>Whether you produce or sell machines that require periodic reviews, or if you perform and manage the maintenance of facilities, safety products, elevators, etc., this functionality will have a high impact on the optimization of work in your company, your profitability, and how the customer perceives your products. </p>
<p>If you sell products that require periodic review (e.g. cars, kitchen machines such as high-end coffee makers, fire extinguishers, etc.), TicTAP NFC tags along with the TicTAP platform will allow you to record revisions. </p>
<p>You only need to create the webapp and create the revision form. The platform allows you to create the pages and forms of the webapp in a visual and intuitive way by dragging and dropping the fields you want in the form to be created. </p>
<p>This way you don’t need to hire an IT team to do it, and you don’t need to rely on it for any future changes you want to make to the pages and forms you create. </p>
<p>Each time a technician makes a review of the appliance or installation, he or she may bring his or her mobile phone closer to the label of the smart object or installation, and enter the information in the form fields that you have configured (revision results, date, etc.). </p>
<p>In this way, if the customer or the technician of the next revision needs to see any data from the previous revision/repair such as the date on which it was made, the maintenance performed, etc., just bring the mobile closer. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-57df8c4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="57df8c4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-your-working-system-min.jpeg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-your-working-system-min.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-your-working-system-min-300x200.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-optimitize-your-working-system-min-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-8df4d4b elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="8df4d4b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Record and report repairs from your mobile phone to improve the quality of your service and customer satisfaction</h3>
<p>In case the machine or installation with TciTAP NFC label breaks down or has a problem in any of its components, the technician can write down the reason for the breakdown and the applied solution.  </p>
<p>In this way, if it breaks down again after a while, it can be checked if the reason is the same, the solution applied last time, etc.</p>
<p><strong>The customer will perceive a sense of control and good management of the breakdown by leaving it registered</strong>. He himself will be able to access this information, manuals etc. of the machine if you want it from his same mobile also approaching the label NFC.</p>
<p>For your company, <b>perform repairs and revisions in this way, will involve an optimization in this type of actions</b>. The records obtained and the actions performed by the technicians and recorded in the form, will be automatically available to the rest of the team. </p>
<p>This allows the data to be manageable, can be automatically reported, control certain aspects to make better decisions in the way you work, etc.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c81c917 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="c81c917" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="469" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-maximize-client-satisfaction-work-system-min.jpeg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-maximize-client-satisfaction-work-system-min.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-maximize-client-satisfaction-work-system-min-300x137.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/07/tictap-maximize-client-satisfaction-work-system-min-768x352.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2dfe699 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2dfe699" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>Offer intelligent objects to differentiate and optimize your work and thus increase sales and customer satisfaction</h2>
<p>As we have seen in this article, <strong>you can convert any machine or parts</strong> that you sell, or <strong>installations</strong> that you control and manage, <strong>in intelligent objects</strong>. </p>
<p>In other words, <strong>elements that contain and provide their own information</strong>. You only need to do this: the <strong>TicTAP platform and the TicTAP NFC</strong> tags.  </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its benefits are many. Today we have highlighted that with TicTAP you can:</span></p>
<ul>
<li>strong>Register reviews</strong></li>
<li>
<li><strong>Register repairs</strong>
<li>strong>Send direct notifications only to customers who will be interested in</strong> the specific notification</li>
<li><strong>Offer a direct contact</strong> to customers</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to know more about converting the products you sell, or the facilities you manage, on smart objects and get the benefits presented in this article, <a href="/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contact us here</a>. </p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-b086c86 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--top tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b086c86" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-fc1b807" data-id="fc1b807" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-75280a4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="75280a4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3 style="text-align: center;">Discover how you can convert your products or installations into intelligent objects, to optimize your work system and increase sales<br /></h3>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b927f0b elementor-align-center elementor-widget__width-inherit elementor-absolute elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="b927f0b" data-element_type="widget" data-settings="{&quot;_position&quot;:&quot;absolute&quot;}" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a href="/en/contact/" class="elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-sm" role="button" id="contactanosdelblog">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">Contac us</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog/how-to-turn-your-products-into-intelligent-items-to-boost-customer-loyalty-and-sales/">How to turn your products into intelligent items to boost customer loyalty and sales.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the Internet of Things (IoT) right for my company? &#8211; IoT versus TicTAP</title>
		<link>/en/blog/me-conviene-internet-of-things-iot-para-mi-empresa-iot-versus-tictap/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria Pascual]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 12:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/me-conviene-internet-of-things-iot-para-mi-empresa-iot-versus-tictap/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, there is more and more talk about the Internet of Things (IoT). More and more IoT-based solutions are being adopted in sectors such as industry, railway, retail, etc. However, despite the many advantages of IoT, we must also consider its drawbacks to determine if it is the best solution for our business. &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/en/blog/me-conviene-internet-of-things-iot-para-mi-empresa-iot-versus-tictap/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Is the Internet of Things (IoT) right for my company? &#8211; IoT versus TicTAP</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog/me-conviene-internet-of-things-iot-para-mi-empresa-iot-versus-tictap/">Is the Internet of Things (IoT) right for my company? &#8211; IoT versus TicTAP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="9462" class="elementor elementor-9462 elementor-8132">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<div class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4190d4c elementor-section-content-top tictap-w2021 tictap-outter-section tictap-text-dark elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4190d4c" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-c16f306" data-id="c16f306" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-0c807f1 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="0c807f1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>In recent years, there is more and more talk about the Internet of Things (IoT). More and more IoT-based solutions are being adopted in sectors such as industry, railway, retail, etc. However, despite the many advantages of IoT, we must also consider its drawbacks to determine if it is the best solution for our business.</p>
<p>TicTAP is not and is not based on IoT. Still, TicTAP has some aspects in common, while in others it overcomes some limitations of the Internet of Things.</p>
<p>Does this mean that TicTAP is better than IoT or vice versa? Not at all. The most honest and realistic answer possible is: &#8220;it depends on your case and the needs of your business.&#8221;</p>
<p>That is why in this article we are going to see the advantages and disadvantages or limitations of IoT and TicTAP so that you can assess which solution best suits your requirements.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-a24a293 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="a24a293" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What is the Internet of Things (IoT)?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-b0ca406 elementor-section-content-top tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b0ca406" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;background_background&quot;:&quot;classic&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-f45c754" data-id="f45c754" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-dc1cf42 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="dc1cf42" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>The IoT consists of the virtual connection between things, processes, people, animals and any real thing or object that we have in our world.</p>
<p>That is, with IoT, any physical object in our environment is capable of automatically communicating with any other physical object without human intervention or human-machine interaction.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-b11bb9d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="b11bb9d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>With Internet of Things, any object can measure and report data. This data can range from simple numbers collected by a sensor, to much more complex discoveries made by devices that measure and analyze multiple data streams at the same time.</p>
<p>In a factory plant, the IoT can be used so that the different machines can quantify and report the operation and performance of the plant, warn about breakdowns or dangerous parameters (excess temperature, etc.).</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e90d66d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="e90d66d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img width="1024" height="655" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min.jpg" class="attachment-large size-large" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min-300x192.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tictap-maintenance-action-4-min-768x491.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-33b5ce3 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="33b5ce3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Advantages of Internet of Things (IoT)</h3>
<p>The main advantages of the Internet of Things are:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong> Predictive and remote maintenance: </strong> IoT devices allow collecting information on their status in real time and sending it to the cloud to be monitored remotely. This information can be used to perform predictive maintenance of the equipment or facilities on which the data was sent.</li>
<li><strong> Communication for automation and control: </strong> IoT enables communication between devices, also known as Machine-to-Machine (M2M) communication.<br />
This direct communication between physical devices without human intervention allows the different devices to work connected to each other, in a transparent way and with less inefficiencies as well as better quality.<br />
Furthermore, as they are connected to the network, they allow them to be controlled digitally and centrally with a wireless infrastructure.</li>
<li><strong> Saving time and money: </strong> Direct communication between machines without human intervention is faster, and it also means that human resources are free from certain tasks since the machines are already synchronized with each other . This frees up time for people who can spend on other tasks, or the number of people needed can be reduced.</li>
<li><strong> Better decisions: </strong> IoT allows you to collect more information, which will always help you to make decisions based on real data. Thus, decisions based on them are likely to be much more realistic and accurate than those based on a more superficial monitoring of the situation or even estimates.</li>
<li><strong> Easier monitoring: </strong> IoT devices can create reports based on the capture of information in real time. In this way the monitoring of the activity or the status of assets, stock, etc. it is much easier and real.</li>
<li><strong> Smart logistics: </strong> One of the biggest difficulties in logistics is getting processes to be well coordinated. IoT devices can send data immediately and in real time. For example, in a transport company, vehicles can be monitored with the help of devices connected via GPS and software. This allows remote management of operations, real-time information on variations and unforeseen events, and therefore a quick response and good coordination.</li>
<li><strong> Increased industrial security: </strong> IoT devices allow monitoring values ​​that may be critical for plant safety, such as temperature or pressure in certain areas, machines or facilities. In this way they allow you to avoid claims.</li>
<li><strong> Increased occupational safety: </strong> Apart from avoiding damage to facilities and their machines, IoT devices are of great help to take care of the physical integrity of your operators and workers. For example, a wearable object can collect biometric data from the user, such as the heart rate. These data allow us to know the status of the worker and determine how to improve working conditions if possible.</li>
<li><strong> Make your company more environmentally friendly: </strong> IoT devices can allow you to obtain information on energy and resource expenditure. They can do it on a single machine or on the entire plant or factory. Information such as the consumption of electricity, water and other resources can be of great value to detect anomalies, excesses, etc. and be able to find a solution. For example, an intelligent machine can use the collected data to enter a state of lower consumption when possible, thus minimizing electricity consumption.</li>
</ol>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-be8a09e elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="be8a09e" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Disadvantages of Internet of Things</h3>
<p>The main advantages are:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong> The information is not encrypted </strong>, so it does not offer total security.<br />
Incompatibilities: IoT is not yet standardized. This leads to compatibility problems in communication and interaction between machines and IoT devices.</li>
<li><strong> The software is not totally secure and can be hacked. </strong></li>
<li><strong> Expensive connection or with limitations such as movement: </strong> If we are talking about IoT devices that work in the same factory, we will not have this problem.<br />
But if you are looking for a solution to be able to track assets, parts or products that can even cross different countries, you cannot count on them always having a connection within reach.<br />
In addition, the device will need to be able to connect via GPS or to the mobile network with its corresponding roaming consequences. All of this makes each IoT device and necessary infrastructure significantly more expensive in situations like this.</li>
</ol>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-548b4b8 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="548b4b8" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What is TicTAP and what does it contribute?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-inner-section elementor-element elementor-element-03d9fb1 elementor-section-content-top tictap-blog-highlighted elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="03d9fb1" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-no">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-ef95df5" data-id="ef95df5" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-87a485d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="87a485d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>The TicTAP system consists of the TicTAP platform and the TicTAP tags that are attached to the assets, machines, facilities, products or objects in general that we want to manage, control and monitor.</p>
<p>Operators or end users will only have to bring their mobile closer to the label to access the data associated with the physical object on the platform.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-inner-column elementor-element elementor-element-5f08672" data-id="5f08672" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ad71c25 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="ad71c25" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p>Therefore, TicTAP&#8217;s approach is very different from IoT. While IoT seeks the interconnection between devices, TicTAP turns lifeless objects into living containers of information.</p>
<p>This solution allows the objects themselves to be those that offer you their own user manual, history of failures or maintenance, traceability, contact between the end user and the supplier or manufacturer (that is, between your customers and your company, for example) , etc.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-bb1d29e elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="bb1d29e" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Advantages of TicTAP</h3>
<p>Thanks to the simplicity behind the idea of ​​TicTAP, our main advantages for your business are:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong> Avoid expensive IoT devices and special wearables, as well as connection infrastructure </strong>, since the connection of the mobile itself is used.</li>
<li><strong> Allow to carry out corrective and predictive maintenance in a more productive, digitized and fully controlled way: </strong> it should be noted that in this case TicTAP has a very different approach from that of IoT devices.<br />
TicTAP allows operators to carry out this type of maintenance and register them at the moment from their own mobile to have the data in a digitized and centralized way. In this way, you can have complete management and control of maintenance.<br />
However, if you are looking to eliminate human intervention and automate maintenance or capture of certain data, you will need IoT devices with sensors, or another type of solution.</li>
<li><strong> Have the peace of mind of having control of the management of assets, facilities or work teams: </strong> TicTAP allows you to have all the data registered by operators and users on the TicTAP platform, completely centralized and controlled by you.</li>
<li><strong> Totally flexible and adaptable to your needs: </strong> the platform allows you to create the forms you need to collect the type of data you want. It allows creating different users and permissions, types of reports, etc. And present all of this to users and operators in a web app format so that they do not have to install anything on their mobile phone, just bring it closer to the TicTAP label of the product or asset, the web app will open to access the data or create records. &lt; / li&gt;</li>
<li><strong> It allows complete traceability: </strong> In the case of parts or machines that must be sent to third-party companies (manufacturers, workshops, etc.), a user can be generated with permission to the company in question so that can record the data that you consider necessary for the traceability you want to have. An example of this is in the railway sector, where a part can even be sent to a company in another country for repair. Giving permission to the provider of the other country, he will only need to access with his mobile to fill in the registration when finishing the repair.</li>
<li><strong> Get savings in time, and therefore money: </strong> in this case the savings is not because the machines communicate and coordinate with each other to carry out processes, but because it allows end users or customers to save time in their interaction with the asset, machine or product.<br />
For example, an appliance manufacturer can attach a TicTAP tag to each of its products. When a customer wants to consult the user manual, ask the manufacturer, etc. You can do this by bringing your mobile closer to the TicTAP label of the appliance to access the data in the web app automatically.<br />
Another very graphic example is that of maintenance workers. They can use TicTAP to record the maintenance or repair performed and have it automatically and digitally in the cloud.</li>
<li><strong> Have an analysis tool available so that you can have the peace of mind of knowing that you are making better decisions: </strong> The data recorded through TicTAP can be used to generate reports on the platform. Analyzing these reports will help you make better decisions based on real data.</li>
<li><strong> Make your company more environmentally friendly: </strong> Again, the approach is different at this point than that offered by IoT devices. With TicTAP your company will be greener because it will reduce the use of paper by disposing and treating all data digitally. In addition, the fact of using the user&#8217;s own mobile eliminates the need for additional wearables and their impact on the environment.</li>
<li><b> Avoid duplication through the integration of TicTAP with your current systems: </b> It is possible to integrate TicTAP with the systems you already have in your company to avoid duplication of processes and data. it will depend on the current systems you have. If you need more information, you can contact us <a href="/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> contact us </a>.</li>
</ol>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d0cdd12 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d0cdd12" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3>Limitations of TicTAP</h3>
<p>We like to be honest and that is why we believe that this information is basic so that you can make the best decision for your company.</p>
<p><strong> The main difference between TicTAP and IoT technology is that TicTAP does not automate or eliminate human intervention. </strong> As we have commented in the previous section, TicTAP ensures that maintenance, access to user manuals of the products, registration in the traceability, update of the stock, etc. be faster, more effective and therefore cheaper. But an operator or user is required to bring their mobile closer to the label to create the data record.</p>
<p>Another differentiating aspect is that TicTAP is not an actively generating data system. <strong> If you require a system that captures and sends certain parameters in real time, an IoT-based solution or another alternative will be more convenient. </strong></p>
<p>Finally, <strong> TicTAP is not intended to centralize the operation of facilities or devices. </strong> If you need to be able to activate or stop, manually or according to a schedule, the devices or machines in one or more buildings, a factory , etc., TicTAP will not be the solution you are looking for either.</p>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-884e6ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="884e6ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2>What is best for me: Internet of Things or TicTAP?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> After everything discussed in this article, we can conclude that an IoT-based solution may be the most appropriate if you need complete process automation minimizing or even eliminating human intervention, obtaining continuous real-time data sent automatically. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> On the other hand, TicTAP may be a good option for your company if you need a much more adaptable, simple and economical solution to, among other things, achieve: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> make maintenance and repairs more effective </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to be able to achieve complete traceability of assets, parts, machines and products </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> be able to have user manuals and records of each asset, machine, installation, etc., </span> &lt; / li&gt;</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> create a channel with customers so they can communicate with you or even send them notifications </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Have a complete record with reports on interventions on machines, installations, etc. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Improve the performance of your workers and operators </span></li>
</ul>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-b086c86 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--top tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="b086c86" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-fc1b807" data-id="fc1b807" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-75280a4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="75280a4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h3 style="text-align: center;">Discover how TicTAP can help you manage the maintenance of facilities and work equipment</h3>
					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-9c3c1c4 tictap-w2021 tictap-banner-demo-blog tictap-banner-demo-blog--bottom tictap-text-white elementor-section-stretched elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="9c3c1c4" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;stretch_section&quot;:&quot;section-stretched&quot;}">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-50a9f53" data-id="50a9f53" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3cf3954 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="3cf3954" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a href="/en/contact/" class="elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-sm" role="button" id="botonContacto_Blog3">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">Haz clic aquí</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/blog/me-conviene-internet-of-things-iot-para-mi-empresa-iot-versus-tictap/">Is the Internet of Things (IoT) right for my company? &#8211; IoT versus TicTAP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/en/">TicTAP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
